<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2019-04-07T20:29:01-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">David Martinez</title><subtitle>David Martinez's personal website</subtitle><author><name>David Martinez</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my new blog and site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/07/welcome-to-my-new-blog-and-site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my new blog and site" /><published>2019-04-07T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-04-07T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/07/welcome-to-my-new-blog-and-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/07/welcome-to-my-new-blog-and-site.html">&lt;p&gt;After a long time thinking about it, I finally commited myself to putting out a personal website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, this is actually its second version. The first one was basically a one-pager without a blog, just to have something &lt;em&gt;out there&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main motivation to publish this personal website is for it to serve as a personal portfolio. Right now I’m in the middle of a self-learning path: I want to become a front-end web developer first and then a full-stack one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I want the website to serve as a showcase for whatever I get to build, while the blog will serve as a repository of insights, lessons learned, skills gained, and so forth. Hopefully, it won’t be too dry, so I might add some personal musings and ramblings, here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin, I’ll let you know I built this website using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as a static site generator and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; for hosting. On later posts I’ll expand on how to use them both to create your own website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, being a native Spanish speaker and a technical translator on my spare time, I want to have this website in both Spanish and English, so I’ll be adding localized versions of all the pages and posts, eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel there’s a lack of Spanish language resources for aspiring devs (at least compared to English ones), so I want to contribute to the community by making learning more accessible for budding coders from Spanish-speaking countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s push this thing out to production! :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Martinez</name></author><category term="content" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">After a long time thinking about it, I finally commited myself to putting out a personal website.</summary></entry></feed>